MADELINE HART

ELLSWORTH, MAINE 04605

(207) 610-4845 | HARTMADELINEJ@GMAIL.COM LinkedIn | Data Analytics Portfolio

SUMMARY

Data analyst with experience across various industries. I am proficient in SQL, Tableau, Excel, data curation, manipulation, and visualization. The projects in my online portfolio, linked above, displays my skills in Data Analytics, Data Management, and Data Visualization. Additionally, I have 4 years of experience in healthcare, in both administrative and clinical settings.

SKILLS

- SQL
- Tableau
- Data Analytics
- Data Manipulation
- Data Visualization
- MS Excel
- Critical Thinking
- Google Workspace
- Data Cleaning
- Communication

- Organization
- Conflict Resolution
- Interpersonal Skills
- Professional Ethics
- Time Management

EDUCATION

Husson University, Bangor, ME Master of Business Administration, B.S. Healthcare Studies

May 2020

- Relevant coursework: Professional Communications, Microcomputing, Microcomputer Spreadsheet Applications, Management Communication, Leadership in Business and Professions, Database Design and Implementation
- My graduate internship took place with the onboarding specialist from Northern Light Blue Hill Hospital. I compiled information
 from 10 different departments in order to develop a new onboarding spreadsheet and checklist with detailed explanations. This
 template that I created was adopted as the formal onboarding tool for all of the Northern Light Practices in the regional area.

DATA ANALYTICS TRAINING

- SQL: Querying and Managing Data, Khan Academy
- Introduction to SQL, <u>DataCamp</u>
- Intermediate SQL, <u>DataCamp</u>
- Joining Data in SQL, <u>DataCamp</u>
- Data Manipulation in SQL, <u>DataCamp</u>
- Exploratory Data Analysis in SQL, <u>DataCamp</u>
- Tableau Creator, <u>Tableau</u>

DATA ANALYTICS & VISUALIZATION PROJECT EXAMPLES

- <u>Public Health Analysis.</u> In this project I used SQL Server to quantify opioid overdose death rates per location, date, and population, and determine locations with the highest and lowest prescription rates.
- <u>Airbnb Dashboard.</u> Quantified profitability by category, region, and date. Visualized average price by region on map of Seattle.

EXPERIENCE

Brewster's Fine Food and Drink, Brewer, ME

October 2021 - Present

Server, Bartender, Floor Manager

- Maintained an 18-table section with a 70 guest capacity, turning over every 1.5 hours and serving an average of 280 guests a day
- Developed relationships with customers while greeting, serving, cleaning/setting tables
- Ensured a positive experience for diners by providing prompt, memorable service, while simultaneously assisting bartender and back of house staff with an adequate sense of urgency

Union River Lobster Pot, Ellsworth, ME

2020 - 2021

Server

- Designed a COVID-19 scripting tool for fellow staff members per manager request
- Followed required guidelines issued by the state in response to the pandemic
- · Collaborated with team to support order preparation, manage efficient deliveries and minimize customer service issues
- Demonstrated robust knowledge of 100+ food and beverage items in order to up-sell to guests, optimizing check totals, as well as to provide amenities such as full wine service

Northern Light Blue Hill Memorial Hospital, Blue Hill, ME

2018 - 2021

Patient Access Representative

- Greeted and registered patients, reviewing and updating charts and insurances, while also completing paperwork for impatient, swing bed, and observation admissions, ensuring all signatures were obtained from patients
- Abided by safety measures established in response to the COVID-19 pandemic
- Managed over 100 calls per day
- Reviewed and corrected claim errors to facilitate smooth processing